<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laura Montenbruck</title>
    <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Laura Montenbruck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fiscal Exchange and Tax Compliance: Strengthening the Social Contract Under Low State Capacity</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/fiscal-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/fiscal-exchange/</guid>
      <description>This article provides evidence that increased salience of public service provision can strengthen the social contract and increase tax compliance in a low-capacity setting. I conduct a field experiment randomizing information about public service provision across 5,494 property owners and tenants in Freetown, Sierra Leone. Receiving information increases property tax payments by 20% on average. The effect is driven by increases in tax compliance on both the extensive and intensive margin. Residents of low-value properties are 7–16 percentage points more likely to pay taxes when informed about public services that are both geographically accessible and respond to the citizens’ most urgent needs, suggesting a benefit-based approach to taxation. Revenue effects are largely driven by residents of high-value properties, who depend less on the public provision of services, and for whom the treatment seems to act as a more general signal of government performance.
&lt;em&gt;Draft available soon.&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Road to Female Empowerment: Evidence from the Free Public Transport Program in New Delhi</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/gender-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/gender-india/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Matters. Biases in Self-Reported Plot Size Data</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/gender-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/gender-plots/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy, Informative, and Cheap? On the Effectiveness of Interactive Voice Response Calls</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/covid-ivr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/covid-ivr/</guid>
      <description>The expansion of modern communication is creating enormous opportunities to gather survey data remotely. To explore this opportunity, we work with two NGOs in three provinces of rural Pakistan in testing two remote survey modalities&amp;mdash; telephonic interviews via enumerators and interactive voice recording. Our results show that interviews led by enumerators largely outperform robocalls in survey quality. In a panel survey with 12,017 beneficiaries, robocalls had lower call pick-up (by 57%), consent (by 92%), and interview completion rates (by 91%). Mistrust in automatized calls, respondent unavailability and low technical skills were self-reported challenges for robocall recipients. Additionally, testing robocall framing, we find evidence of bias towards female voice recordings in acquiring consent. Medical and religious contextualization also improve outcomes such as overall item response. Robocalls are also less cost-effective in our sample, where a completed interview using IVR is approximately 88 times as expensive as one conducted via an enumerator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Involving Religious Leaders in COVID-19 Awareness Campaigns: Implications for Behavioral Change</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/covid-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/covid-awareness/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of Women&#39;s Rights</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/womens-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/womens-rights/</guid>
      <description>Two centuries ago, in most countries around the world, women were unable to vote, had no say over their own children or property, and could not obtain a divorce. Women have gradually gained rights in many areas of life, and this legal expansion has been closely intertwined with economic development. We aim to understand the drivers behind these reforms. To this end, we distinguish between four types of women’s rights—economic, political, labor, and body—and document their evolution over the past 50 years across countries. We summarize the political-economy mechanisms that link economic development to changes in women’s rights and show empirically that these mechanisms account for a large share of the variation in women’s rights across countries and over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents caused by kerosene lamps—New evidence from African household data</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/kerosene-lamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/kerosene-lamps/</guid>
      <description>The use of kerosene for lighting, cooking, and heating in developing countries is often considered a major health threat as it can cause accidents like thermal inju- ries, poisonings, fires, or explosions. The evidence to prove this is extremely scarce, though. The present paper is one of the first to investigate the link between kerosene-based lighting and accidents at the household level. We use survey data from 3,326 nonelectrified households in Burkina Faso, Rwanda, Senegal, and Zambia and observe very heterogeneous kerosene lamp usage rates. In some regions, accidents with kerosene lamps occur in a substantial share of the population, but the absolute incidence is rather low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/2023-gender_ghana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/2023-gender_ghana/</guid>
      <description>#&amp;mdash; #title: &amp;ldquo;Sexual Harassment and Women&amp;rsquo;s Career Choices: Evidence from Ghanaian Universities&amp;rdquo; #author: &amp;ldquo; Sarah Deschênes&amp;rdquo; #date: &amp;lsquo;2023-08-19&amp;rsquo; #slug: gender-ghana #tags:
- Work in progress #summary: &amp;quot; &amp;quot; #featured: yes #full_abstract: no #show_links: yes #links: #show_post_date: false #&amp;mdash;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
