<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications and Working Papers on Laura Montenbruck</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/publications-and-working-papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications and Working Papers on Laura Montenbruck</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/publications-and-working-papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fiscal Exchange and Tax Compliance: Strengthening the Social Contract Under Low State Capacity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/fiscal-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/fiscal-exchange/</guid>
      <description>This article provides evidence that increased salience of public service provision can strengthen the social contract and increase tax compliance in a low-capacity setting. I conduct a field experiment randomizing information about public service provision across 5,494 property owners and tenants in Freetown, Sierra Leone. Receiving information increases property tax payments by 20% on average. The effect is driven by increases in tax compliance on both the extensive and intensive margin. Residents of low-value properties are 7–16 percentage points more likely to pay taxes when informed about public services that are both geographically accessible and respond to the citizens’ most urgent needs, suggesting a benefit-based approach to taxation. Revenue effects are largely driven by residents of high-value properties, who depend less on the public provision of services, and for whom the treatment seems to act as a more general signal of government performance. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Job Market Paper&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Faith: Effects of an Imam-led Information Campaign on Labor Supply and Social Interactions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/covid-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/covid-awareness/</guid>
      <description>We conduct a randomized controlled trial in rural Pakistan, comparing the effects of a remote awareness campaign with and without Imam-led loudspeaker endorsements on strategies to contain disease spread. Our results show that labor supply and social interactions decrease significantly only when religious leaders support the campaign, particularly among men. These results cannot be explained by differences in the mode or frequency of treatment across groups. Our findings—compatible with predictions from a model that analyzes the individual trade-off between prevention benefits and losses from forgone income—highlight the critical role of religious figures in shaping public responses to health crises.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of Women&#39;s Rights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/womens-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/womens-rights/</guid>
      <description>Two centuries ago, in most countries around the world, women were unable to vote, had no say over their own children or property, and could not obtain a divorce. Women have gradually gained rights in many areas of life, and this legal expansion has been closely intertwined with economic development. We aim to understand the drivers behind these reforms. To this end, we distinguish between four types of women’s rights—economic, political, labor, and body—and document their evolution over the past 50 years across countries. We summarize the political-economy mechanisms that link economic development to changes in women’s rights and show empirically that these mechanisms account for a large share of the variation in women’s rights across countries and over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accidents caused by kerosene lamps—New evidence from African household data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/kerosene-lamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/kerosene-lamps/</guid>
      <description>The use of kerosene for lighting, cooking, and heating in developing countries is often considered a major health threat as it can cause accidents like thermal inju- ries, poisonings, fires, or explosions. The evidence to prove this is extremely scarce, though. The present paper is one of the first to investigate the link between kerosene-based lighting and accidents at the household level. We use survey data from 3,326 nonelectrified households in Burkina Faso, Rwanda, Senegal, and Zambia and observe very heterogeneous kerosene lamp usage rates. In some regions, accidents with kerosene lamps occur in a substantial share of the population, but the absolute incidence is rather low.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
