<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Job market paper on Laura Montenbruck</title>
    <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/tags/job-market-paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job market paper on Laura Montenbruck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/tags/job-market-paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fiscal Exchange and Tax Compliance: Strengthening the Social Contract Under Low State Capacity</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/fiscal-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/fiscal-exchange/</guid>
      <description>This article provides evidence that increased salience of public service provision can strengthen the social contract and increase tax compliance in a low-capacity setting. I conduct a field experiment randomizing information about public service provision across 5,494 property owners and tenants in Freetown, Sierra Leone. Receiving information increases property tax payments by 20% on average. The effect is driven by increases in tax compliance on both the extensive and intensive margin. Residents of low-value properties are 7–16 percentage points more likely to pay taxes when informed about public services that are both geographically accessible and respond to the citizens’ most urgent needs, suggesting a benefit-based approach to taxation. Revenue effects are largely driven by residents of high-value properties, who depend less on the public provision of services, and for whom the treatment seems to act as a more general signal of government performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
