<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Laura Montenbruck</title>
    <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/tags/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Laura Montenbruck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/tags/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of Women&#39;s Rights</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/womens-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/womens-rights/</guid>
      <description>Two centuries ago, in most countries around the world, women were unable to vote, had no say over their own children or property, and could not obtain a divorce. Women have gradually gained rights in many areas of life, and this legal expansion has been closely intertwined with economic development. We aim to understand the drivers behind these reforms. To this end, we distinguish between four types of women’s rights—economic, political, labor, and body—and document their evolution over the past 50 years across countries. We summarize the political-economy mechanisms that link economic development to changes in women’s rights and show empirically that these mechanisms account for a large share of the variation in women’s rights across countries and over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents caused by kerosene lamps—New evidence from African household data</title>
      <link>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/kerosene-lamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lauramontenbruck.github.io/research/kerosene-lamps/</guid>
      <description>The use of kerosene for lighting, cooking, and heating in developing countries is often considered a major health threat as it can cause accidents like thermal inju- ries, poisonings, fires, or explosions. The evidence to prove this is extremely scarce, though. The present paper is one of the first to investigate the link between kerosene-based lighting and accidents at the household level. We use survey data from 3,326 nonelectrified households in Burkina Faso, Rwanda, Senegal, and Zambia and observe very heterogeneous kerosene lamp usage rates. In some regions, accidents with kerosene lamps occur in a substantial share of the popula- tion, but the absolute incidence is rather low.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
